So we're working with this grid world example and looking for
我们介绍了这个网格世界示例
the best policy that leads us to a goal state as quickly as possible.
并讲解了尽快实现目标状态的最佳策略
So, let's start with a very,
我们先从一个非常糟糕的策略开始
very bad policy so that we can understand why it's bad,
看看它为何很糟糕
and then work to improve it.
然后逐渐改善它
Specifically, we'll look at a policy where the agent
具体而言 在此策略中
visits every state in this very roundabout manner,
智能体将以这种非常迂回的方式抵达每个状态
and we can ignore the transition that the agent will never take under the policy.
我们将忽略智能体始终无法在此策略下采取的变动
So now, towards understanding why this policy is bad,
为了理解为何此策略很糟糕
let's calculate the cumulative reward that will result.
我们计算下最终的累积奖励
If the agent starts in the top left corner of
如果智能体从该网格的左上角开始
the world and follows this policy to get to the goal state,
并按照该策略抵达目标状态
it just collects all of the reward along the way.
它只是一路收集奖励
So that's negative one plus negative one,
即 -1 加 -1
plus negative one again,
再加 -1 等等
and so on, where if I add up all the rewards along the way,
将所有奖励相加
I get negative six.
结果是 -6
Let's say we're not discounting or that the discount rate is one,
假设我们没有进行折扣 即折扣率是 1
we'll keep track of this negative six and remember,
我们记下这个 -6
that it represents the fact that if we start at the state at the top left corner,
它表示从左上角开始
and then just follow the policy for all time steps,
然后在所有时间步都遵守该策略
that results in a return of negative six.
结果是 -6
But now, say, instead the agent started one location over to the right.
现在假设智能体在向右一个网格的位置开始
Then, what return would be likely to follow under the same policy?
那么对于同一策略 回报可能是多少？
Again, we just sum up all the rewards that the agent receives along the way,
我们将智能体在一路上获得的奖励相加
and when we do that,
相加之后
we get a return of negative five,
回报是 -5
and let's also keep track of that.
同样记下该数据
We can continue and do this for every state in the world.
继续下去并对每个状态执行这一流程
It makes sense to think of the goal state as resulting in the return of zero.
目标状态的回报应该是 0
After all, if the agent starts at the goal
毕竟 如果智能体从目标开始
the episode ends immediately and no reward is received.
这一阶段立即结束 没有获得奖励
In this way, no matter where the agent starts in the world,
这样的话 无论智能体从哪里开始
we have a way of keeping track of the return that follows.
我们都可以记录获得的回报
This way of analyzing this horrible policy will help us to improve it.
以这种方式分析这个糟糕的策略可以帮助我们完善它
But before we get into exactly how to do that,
但是在完善之前
let's attach a bit of notation and terminology to this process we just followed.
我们来介绍下这一流程涉及的记法和术语
You can think of this grid of numbers as a function of the environment state.
你可以将这个数字网格看做环境状态函数
For each state, it has a corresponding number,
对于每个状态 它都有一个对应的数字
and we refer to this function as the state-value function.
我们将此函数称为状态值函数
For each state, it yields the return that's likely to follow if
对于每个状态 它都生成当智能体从该状态开始
the agent starts in that state and then follows the policy for all time steps,
然后在所有时间步都遵循该策略时可能会获得的回报
but it's more common to see it equivalently expressed but with a bit more notation.
但是更常见的情况是表示为公式记法
Before I show you that notation,
在介绍该公式记法之前
I warn you that it looks a bit complicated,
我要提醒下 它看起来会比较复杂
but it's equivalent to what we've already discussed. And here it is.
但是对应的正是我们已经讨论的知识 这个公式是这样的
The state-value function for a policy pi is a function of the environment state.
策略 π 的状态值函数是环境状态的函数
For each state s, it tells us the expected discounted return,
对于每个状态 s 它都告诉我们
if the agent started in that state s,
如果智能体从该状态 s 开始
and then use the policy to choose its actions for all time steps,
然后在所有时间步根据该策略选择动作 预期的折扣回报是多少
the state value function will always correspond to a particular policy.
状态值函数将始终对应特定的策略
So if we change the policy,
如果我们更改策略
we change the state-value function,
就会更改状态值函数
and we typically did note the function with the lowercase
我们通常用小写的 v 表示该函数
v with the corresponding policy in the subscript.
并用下标表示对应的策略